You said fentanyl at the beginning and
you are right. A lot of that product is
not coming from Venezuela. It's coming
from Mexico. It's coming from China
specifically. It's a very broad sword
this narco-terrorism designation. I
think that it's being used to conduct
some regime change. Right. So, that's
the key point here. I think there's
something global hope happening here and
this is just one part of the chessboard.
Perhaps this is a way to keep the
Chinese out of the Caribbean, to keep
the Chinese out of Venezuela. You can
say you're doing it in order to stop the
flow of drugs even if that's not really
the case. What will the CIA be doing
right now in Venezuela? To affect a
coup, if if you want it to be quick,
everything that's important is going to
take place in the capital. You have to
control the radio and television
stations. You have to surround the
presidential palace and you have to
control the major intersections in the
city. Once that happens, all the other
dominoes begin to fall.
[Music]
The White House is very clear about why
it's ramping up pressure on Venezuela.
Drugs, Venezuelan cartels are shipping
fentanyl into the United States, they
say, with the full complicity of
President Maduro. The socialist leader
is thereby contributing to a crisis
which has killed hundreds of thousands
of Americans, justifying a state of war
readiness and a series of deadly air
strikes on small Venezuelan boats. But
not everybody's convinced the majority
of all fentanyl in the US is made using
Chinese chemicals by cartels in Mexico
from where almost all of it is imported.
Well, Ed Calderon is a combat
instructor, security consultant and a
cartels expert and he joins me now. Ed,
thank you very much indeed for joining
me.
Thank you.
What do you make of this? I mean, Donald
Trump is accusing Nicolas Maduro, the
President of Venezuela, of conducting a
narco war, of running a narco-terrorist
cartel. You're a cartel expert, is he
right?
The connections between his family and
the
movement of cocaine into the United
States has long known. 2015 saw two of
his nephews basically arrested for some
of these issues.
The military in Venezuela has been
engaging in these activities for years
now.
It is something that is happening.
Cocaine though.
You said fentanyl at the beginning and
you are right. A lot of that product is
not coming from Venezuela. It's coming
from Mexico. It's coming from overseas,
China specifically.
It's a very broad sword this
narco-terrorism designation. I think
that it's being used in this case to
conduct some
regime change.
Right. So, that's the key point here is
that many people think it's a cover for
regime change aspirations by the US
government under Donald Trump.
And many people speculate it's because
Venezuela has a lot of oil
and that you have a socialist leader who
they think is there by default.
The last election, he should have left
but he's refused to go and so on. Um
And there's also a kind of like
an anomaly here where if you were
choosing one of the countries in that
region as a place to target for imports
of cocaine or illegal drugs generally,
then you would probably choose Colombia
not Venezuela. So, why why Venezuela?
10% of cocaine This is These are
government US government numbers back
from 2009. 10% of cocaine coming into
the United States was coming from
Venezuela. The numbers are now
completely impossible to know because of
some of the things that are happening on
the seaside.
The military has long since been known
for their association with certain
cartels, specifically the Sinaloa cartel
when it was existing back in the day.
Chapo Guzman was arrested speaking to
members of the military trying to figure
out how to get a
close connection.
Yes, Colombia should be on that list as
well and I think it might be on that
list.
I think many countries in South America
and North America, that being Mexico,
are probably on that list.
They are attempting to do something in
Venezuela that they might want to
replicate other parts of the another
part of the continent, I think. Um
It's It's It's hard to It's hard to
It's hard to blame the United States as
far as how it views the the the
situation in Venezuela. I mean, I'm
currently in Sweden and I've spoken with
some people who are refugees of
Venezuela here and they've explained to
me how the current government has
basically stolen their lands,
put in people that they know and family
members that they know in in positions
of power in that region and basically
took everything for themselves. Uh
They're looking for every single way
every single way of making money in that
region and the military is very much
involved in in in some of these
activities. So, it's it's it's a it's a
real thing.
Now, how big of a threat is versus other
parts of the other parts of the
continent and and prioritize prioritize
That's that's where I I know people are
questioning
resources specifically in that region.
But the the Venezuelan government itself
has single-handedly destroyed most of
its ability to process a lot of the fuel
that it extracts from the ground. So,
here we are. Right. So, you've got a
sort of chaotic regime, probably
illegitimate now. Um and acting with
impunity.
Um and that may be a collection of
explanations for why the US is
considering regime change. Of course,
Donald Trump has always been very
anti-regime change and spoken out
against regime change and thinking
America should be America first and
shouldn't be interviewing intervening in
foreign countries. So,
what do you think is going on here with
his change of mind if that's what
happens?
I mean, Venezuela has very clear ties to
the United States' enemies abroad. I
mean, Russia and China. Coincidental I
mean, and we have to mention that they
are nowhere to be seen realistically as
far as coming to their aid.
I think there's something global hope
happening here and this is just one part
of the chessboard that the United States
is playing.
This It's unsustainable. Whatever is
going on there as far as the governments
and and just I mean, I get to speak to a
lot of refugees and people. I do a lot
of charity work and I to speak to
specifically to the immigrant situation.
There is something happening there that
is driving humanity away from that
country that is undeniable. Now,
is that a just cause to blow up a drug
boats in in the ocean without really
knowing exactly what's going on there?
And and the people that are on those
boats, this is beyond my
wheelhouse.
Um but
people are people there are expecting an
attack any day now and people that are
not there who are living abroad are
fueled with the
possibility that the regime is going
away.
And it's hard to It's hard to ignore
those voices as well. There has been a
mass exodus of people from Venezuela,
hasn't there?
Yes.
We saw the migrant caravans being
conformed by many many Venezuelans going
through Mexico. Some of these
encampments
were full of them. Um
We We have
We have this narrative in some in some
places where some of these where all of
these migrants are criminal, which is
not the case. Again, I've I've been
speaking to some in Switzerland who are,
you know, highly educated people. People
that come from that come came from
wealthy families that were pretty much
set in in Venezuela that were
stripped of land, stripped of property,
stripped of everything they they they
know they they owned and and basically
left to the wind.
This this broad stroke that sometimes it
gets labeled on some of these migrants
as all being criminal, as all being part
of a
part of these international
transnational gangs is is is false.
But yes, the mass the mass humanity that
has been moving out of the country and
crossing the border specifically under
the time of the Biden administration
where that border was basically wide
open,
a lot of those were Venezuelan. A lot of
a lot of the a lot of the
There is a lot There's this The thing
gets told a lot by the president right
now in the United States about
prisons being emptied.
That was actually That actually did
happen and prisons were emptied and
Mexico specifically right now and I have
friends who are working at a federal
level right now there are dealing with
fentanyl threats in Mexico City, for
example, where they're setting up
They're clearing out cartels. They're
local Mexican cartels with their their
ongoing efforts against the cartels in
Mexico.
And now you're seeing fentanyl the
fentanyl
people basically setting up shop in
Mexico. So, yes, it is it is a it is a
real threat that is happening not only
in
not only throughout Latin America, but
in Mexico and yes, the United States as
well. Speaking to some of my
counterparts who are active there that
they've seen this threat and it is a
real one.
But it's not all of them. Again, this
broad stroke that this broad brush that
gets painted against all of them as
criminals or as some sort of undesirable
people is
is just
It's just not the case. What is the
general view amongst the Venezuelans
you've talked to about the likelihood
that these boats that are being targeted
are being
gang operated, they are criminals and
they are trying to bring in large
amounts of drugs into the United States
and therefore are legitimate targets?
It's It's It's It's
probably I mean, this is a transport
job. These drug boats are drug boats.
There's no denying that they are moving
uh quantities of drugs through the
ocean. Now, are they going to make it
all the way to Florida
uh with the fuel they have on those
boats? Probably not. Uh they're
transporting from one point to another.
Most of the trafficking has moved to the
ground. That's where the the the the
real threat as far as drug trafficking
happens. Everything's Everything most of
it is now moving through the ground. You
have on the Pacific side of the the
Navy, the US Navy, and then the and
and on the the Caribbean side, it's it's
full of the it's it's full of government
ships.
Uh the sentiment is uh mixed.
Um
you have to realize that a lot of these
people that are probably on those boats
are poor, marginalized people. I don't
think they're probably any They're I
don't think they're any sort of military
officials on those boats. They're kids.
They're they're minors maybe on some of
these boats.
Uh and, you know, if you're a human
being and you have any sort of sentiment
towards towards humanity, seeing
seeing them get blown up in the middle
of the ocean and then survivors getting
uh blown up again is going to be
something that's going to hit you in a
certain way.
Um But will it will it act though uh as
a deterrent, which is obviously what the
Trump administration is saying? Is it
they they believe if they keep doing
this the number of boats bringing these
drugs over, which as you say it's it's
you're you're certain they are drug
boats, that if they want to stop the
drugs coming, this will be a very
effective deterrent.
It is a very effective deterrent. Fear
is there, I have to say. It is a very
effective deterrent. The trafficking
side of things on both sides of the
ocean We don't hear a lot about some of
the boats that have been that that that
have been um taken out on the
coasts of coasts of Mexico, but there
have been a few as well. And um speaking
to people that are in law enforcement
still currently active on both sides of
the border, both in Mexico and the
United States, they have seen
some sort of
stoppage at least a straw of traffic on
the on the ocean. So, it is working on
that end. But,
we also have to realize that uh
drug prices and the availability of some
of these substances hasn't really
diminished or moved in any significant
way. So,
yes,
there is an effect on the ocean and the
way things are being trafficked and fear
is on there Fear is on Fear is in the
water, basically.
But, the effects of of of these policies
haven't been felt in the cities and it
on the streets in in the United States.
Um
So, that's I I think that's where that's
where at least people aligned of things
were analyzing this closely
haven't really seen that needle move.
So, then
is this working? will be the question.
Right, because these drug gangs they're
very sophisticated, they're very well
resourced, and presumably if they lose a
particular way of transporting their
drugs, they'll find another way.
That's it. Yeah, that's it. Here's
Colombia
is another source. Mexico is another
source. So, there there's a lot of
sources. Right now, this very broad
sword that is this this this terrorist
designation
is being utilized in Venezuela for many
reasons. And I think um
I think we all know that there there are
many more reasons beyond that of this
being a specific counter I mean also,
there's a kind of
There's a kind of obvious double
standards that's just emerged this week
where you've got President Trump at a
cabinet meeting yesterday saying anyone
who brings drugs into the US will die.
Let's watch the clip.
Mr. President, if you are declaring war
against these cartels and Congress is
likely to
um approve of that process, why not just
ask for a declaration of war?
Well, I don't think we're going to
necessarily ask for a declaration of
war. I think we're just going to kill
people that are bringing drugs into our
country. Okay? We're going to kill them,
you know? They're going to be like dead.
Okay?
Now, they're strong words, but then he
has literally just pardoned and released
the former president of Honduras, Juan
Orlando Hernández, who in 2024, just
last year, was found guilty of
conspiring to import cocaine to the
United States and sentenced to 45 years
in prison. There'll be many people
looking at that going, "Hang on.
How does that work?"
It's um
from what I can tell and from what I've
seen as far as that release, uh he's
basically saying that it it was a
political motivated arrest and that he
was framed for for those crimes by the
past administration. The veracity of
that is
uh
It's it's beyond me if if that is a true
statement or not.
Um
His threats of death, his threats his
threats of killing people that are going
to cross drugs into into into United
States
is something that I have to tell you,
Piers, it resonates a lot with people
that have been the victims of these
substances and in these criminal
organizations on many parts in many
parts of the continent. Um myself
included. Um
These criminal organizations have taken
over vast amounts of territory, become
governors and government in in in in
some of the places they control, and the
effects of this I mean, I grew up on the
streets of Tijuana.
And I've went from there to going to
places like Portland and seeing some of
the effects of some of these substances
and how it consumes people. Not even
that. I mean,
I have friends who have kids 17, 16 who
just took some drugs at a party um
and didn't wake up.
I understand some of the anger and some
of the feelings around some of these
substances and some of the people that
voted and got the president to the White
House and why this is
such
uh
a motivating topic uh for for for the
populace.
Um
Now,
this designation and how it's being
utilized and the scope of it, I think is
what people are now going to
backing up a bit and trying to see if
it's actually feasible or not to be
utilizing this designation to
continue on with these efforts.
I have a feeling that this is going to
continue on and I think whatever happens
in Venezuela is going to be a template
for further actions of in other parts of
the continent.
Do you think it is more likely than not
that the US will invade Venezuela?
I think I think it's
I think I think the pressure right now
is to make Maduro reach a deal
and extract himself from Venezuela.
I'm expecting a plane flying out of
Venezuela landing in Russia at any time
uh Syria style any day now. Hopefully,
that is the the where we're headed. Um
Speaking to people that know more about
military invasions than I do, Venezuela
is a very it's going to be a very
difficult thing to
to hold and to and to control if the
regime falls
and turns into a guerrilla force.
We must we we must understand that
Venezuela the Venezuelan military is one
thing, but also there's a bunch of
guerrilla forces in in in and around
Venezuela that are
aligned with the regime that will
basically take our
take up arms
against whoever
stays in power. And
we're going to look at it We're going to
be looking at another Afghanistan or
another or another Iraq as far as not
only
the battle not being concluded when the
invasion concludes,
but when the death toll rises from
trying to hold that space. And that's
not even taken into account the
the mass amount of humanity that is
already struggling with things like
potable water or food in in some of
these regions by the regimes' complete
mishandling of everything when it comes
to government.
So, now add onto that the
the war aspect, and I think we're in for
some
pretty horrible humanitarian crisis.
Hopefully,
Maduro and his
uh family
jump on a plane with a bunch of gold
bricks like like a lot of people that
have followed kind of his suit and uh
fly to Russia or China, whoever takes
them.
Yeah.
Let's hope that he sees sense. It could
get very messy. Uh A cool one. Thank you
very much indeed for joining me. I
appreciate it.
Thank you so much.
Today's show is sponsored by Oxford
Natural, makers of the Optimum Day and
Optimum Night all-natural supplements.
Thousands of Brits and Americans are
already taking them with incredible
results. Optimum Day boosts your energy
and supports weight loss throughout the
day. Optimum Night helps you relax and
get deep, refreshing sleep. They have
countless success stories, including
from some very familiar faces. England
legend Michael Owen, who lost 40 lb.
AFTV's Robbie, who lost more than 100
lb. To watch their full stories and many
more, scan the QR code on your screen or
visit oxfordnatural.com/piers.
And here's the best part. Use the code
piers and get 70% off your first order.
Yes, 70% off with the code piers.
Christmas is peak time for online
shopping sprees, but that also means
it's peak time for hackers and data
brokers who steal your information
online. The solution's very simple. Use
ExpressVPN to shut them down. Top-tier
encryption keeps your activity hidden,
even on dodgy public Wi-Fi, which is
perfect for holiday travel. You You set
your location to 105 different
countries, which lets you access content
from all over the world. Users save
hundreds on streaming and even plane
tickets with ExpressVPN all for $3.49
a month. It's a no-brainer. I use it and
you should, too. Right now, you can get
an extra 4 months of ExpressVPN if you
go to expressvpn.com/piers.
That's ExpressVPN's lowest price ever
plus four extra months of service. Just
scan the QR code on the screen or go to
expressvpn.com/piers.
From plotting to lace Fidel Castro's
diving suit with poison fungus to the
execution of Che Guevara, the CIA has a
long and troubled history of meddling in
the countries south of its own border,
especially when socialists are involved.
President Trump says he's authorized
secret CIA missions inside Venezuela
along with a not-so-secret massing of
naval forces in the Caribbean Sea. For
his view on what's going on and why, I'm
joined by the former CIA officer and
whistleblower John Kiriakou. John,
welcome back to Uncensored.
Thank you so much for having me. It's
always a pleasure. So, what's going on
here? Is the US using the
obviously uh genuine threat of drug
cartels bringing drugs into United
States via these boats as an excuse for
regime change? And if so, why?
I think probably yes, which which I
think also is unfortunate because
you know, there are legitimate reasons
to to put pressure on the likes of
Nicolas Maduro, but you don't have to
threaten invasion to do that. I I think
that what we're seeing here is a
multi-faceted
program.
First of all, the the US has a very,
very long history, of course, going back
to the Monroe Doctrine in in Latin
America. Much of that history has been
very ugly. We could sit here and talk
for hours about the United Fruit
Company, for example, and the overthrow
of a democratically elected government
in in Guatemala. We could talk about
military dictatorships in in South
America as recently as the 1980s.
But but this is this is unusual because
we've never used drugs as as a reason to
to
institute regime change. Let's let's put
it that way.
I I think that's only a part of it,
though, Piers. I think that there's a
bigger picture issue at play here, and
that is China's influence in Latin
America. Look at it this way.
The Venezuelans are sitting on an ocean
of oil. That oil happens to be very
dirty. It's very, very high in sulfur.
And for many decades, the only place
where that oil could be refined properly
was at refineries in southern Texas.
Well, now the Chinese are building a
refinery in the Caribbean, and the
Chinese will be willing and able to
refine high-sulfur Venezuelan oil.
Perhaps this is a way to keep the
Chinese out of the Caribbean, to keep
the Chinese out of Venezuela. Certainly,
having a regime change operation
successful in Venezuela would make the
Colombian military very happy. And then,
at the same time, you can you can say
you're doing it in order to stop to stop
the flow of drugs, even if that's not
really the case. The history of regime
change involving the United States is
pretty messy.
Is there any guarantee that if the US
committed troops on the ground to
actually invade Venezuela, it wouldn't
end up
like Iraq, for example? I mean,
Venezuela has even more oil than Iraq.
Um you know, could it could it turn into
another Iraq if
the US is not careful?
Oh, I think the answer is yes. You
you've hit on something very important
here.
This is something that the United States
has traditionally been very bad at. It's
easy It's easy to go into a country and
overthrow its leadership. That's the
easy part. The difficult part is what to
do next. Regime change is one thing.
Regime or nation-building, rather.
Nation-building is an entirely different
thing.
You know, I sat in a I sat in a meeting,
I think you'll get a kick out of this. I
sat in a meeting the night before the US
invasion of Iraq. The meeting was
chaired by Vice President Cheney. I was
the note-taker for CIA Director George
Tenet. And it was the Vice President,
the Secretary of State, the Secretary of
Defense, the Chairman of the Joint
Chiefs, the CIA Director, all the big
principals.
And one of the briefers was the Director
of CENTCOM, the Central Command, and he
said, almost offhandedly,
that
things will go well tomorrow when we
cross the border into Iraq, the Iraqis
will throw flowers at us. And he said,
"If things go as planned, we can be in
Tehran by August." And Director Tenet
turned off his microphone, and he turned
to me, and he said, "Did he say Tehran
or did he say Baghdad?" I said, "He said
Tehran."
And George says, "Are these people
insane?"
Well, the answer is yes. Oftentimes,
they are insane. At least they they
think so highly of themselves and their
own ability or the Pentagon's ability
to institute forced change and then to
live happily ever after.
You would think that they would learn
their lesson when we fail time after
time after time. And isn't isn't there a
clear I mean, isn't there a clear a
lesson
from what's happened in Syria, right?
Where if it's organic and it comes from
within and it's Syrian-driven by Syrian
people who want to affect their own
regime change, actually, it can be far
quicker, far more effective, and far
less messy. Look, we have to we have to
wait and see what happens in Syria, but
certainly, so far, it'd be hard to argue
that the new regime is worse than the
Assad regime.
And America didn't have to do very much,
right? And in fact, Putin backed exactly
right.
>> there seems to me there's an obvious
template there for organic regime change
always being a better option than
enforced regime change, particularly
from the US, who are often get
themselves corralled into really messy
situation for long periods of time.
Oh, I think you've hit the nail on the
head. And Syria ought to be
the template for how we move forward on
these. Listen, there's there's no
problem
from a policy perspective to supply
aid, for example, whether it's economic
aid or or military aid to the Kurds or
to, you know, free Syrian fighters.
Oddly enough, we had the CIA most
recently in Syria. We had the CIA
supplying Al-Qaeda and the Pentagon
supplying a completely different group
that was at war with Al-Qaeda. So, we
almost came out on top in spite of
ourselves there, but but I think you're
right. I think Syria is something that
should be studied in the halls of
international intelligence services and,
you know, implemented with more of a
hands-off approach. Going into a country
and just occupying it and and thinking
that you're going to succeed just
because we're the good guys is not a
workable plan.
What will the CIA be doing right now in
Venezuela? We know that there's no great
surprise, but given all the backdrop of
a potential invasion, or maybe it's a
double bluff by Trump, and he's just
trying to get Maduro to to leave the
country, which could well be what he's
trying to do. Um but what would the CIA
be doing?
Yeah, that's that's a good observation,
too. This could be a bluff. But let's
assume for the for the sake of this
question that it's not a bluff. The CIA
would be doing everything from trying to
to recruit or to influence
the owners of the Venezuelan media
to place anti-Maduro articles or or
opinion pieces or pro-American articles
or opinion pieces, to arming factions
that may be available to them in
Caracas. Listen, to to affect a coup, if
if you want it to be quick, and and it's
a place like Venezuela where everything
that's important is going to take place
in the capital, you have to control the
radio and television stations, you have
to surround the presidential palace, and
you have to control the major
intersections in the city. Once that
happens, all the other dominoes begin to
fall.
So, it would be like overthrowing the
Greek government in 1967. You don't have
to attack and invade and occupy the
entire country. You just need the center
of the city along with the presidential
palace and the parliament. I think
that's the plan in this case.
>> interestingly, as we saw in Ukraine, for
example, clearly, the Russians thought
they could steam into Kyiv, overthrow
Zelenskyy, and this would all be over
quite quickly. And here we are, years
later, and it didn't happen. Often, the
best-laid plans look straightforward on
paper. You make assumptions, but cold,
hard reality
can kick in and take you to places you
never imagined.
That's right. Look at Afghanistan. After
years and years, Hamid Karzai was really
little more than the mayor of Kabul, and
even then, he didn't control all of
Kabul. 20 years of American occupation,
more than a trillion dollars spent, and
and still
we're we're facing we're facing enemies
as soon as we leave the city limits.
It's not a way to run a war.
Maduro, many people think he's there
illegitimately now, that following the
last election, he lost it, and he's just
refused to go. What is the reality about
that?
You know, I consider myself to be a
person who approaches these issues from
the, you know, slightly left of center,
but I've never believed that Maduro was
legitimate.
Uh I I've always believed that he was he
was pumping up these numbers, stealing
these elections. Not to say that the
right is is the savior of the country.
We don't frankly know what the
Venezuelan right is going to look like
once it begins to run things. But but
I've always believed that that Maduro
had serious legitimacy problems.
So,
what's your hunch about what he may do?
We've seen enough of him now for a few
years to
get a kind of measure of the man. Is he
the kind you think who when confronted
with the possibility of an invasion and
perhaps his death that he will just pull
a an Assad and get on a plane?
I think that's the likelihood. Now, the
CIA just three or four weeks ago,
according to Maduro's private pilot, the
CIA tried to recruit the pilot with the
idea that were Maduro to run, he would
get on the plane, say "Take me to
Havana." Instead, the pilot takes him to
Key West, and the FBI is there to arrest
him and charge him with international
narcotics trafficking. So, I think that
Maduro
probably has laid plans to leave if he
needs to leave quickly. If he does need
to leave quickly, I think he'll probably
end up in Havana, possibly in Moscow.
But uh but yeah, I think that's probably
that's probably the way it would play
out. Now, I think that we would get a
very
I think we would get a better idea of
what the plans are if we were to watch
those military leaders closest to him.
If we begin to see fissures among the
military leadership in Venezuela, then
it it won't be long for Maduro after
that. And how easy would it be for the
CIA to arrange his death?
You know, I think that's a lot of harder
than most people uh would expect. It's
not It's not the '60s or the early '70s
anymore where the CIA is, you know, a
completely renegade organization and it
just goes around overthrowing
governments and assassinating world
leaders. Now, there actually is at least
some congressional oversight. There's a
a bureaucratic process by which they
would have to go through, and it's quite
difficult because it's not just the CIA
coming up with an idea and then going to
the president to approve the idea. There
are layers and layers of attorneys in
the in the Justice Department's Office
of Legal Counsel and the National
Security uh Council's Office of Legal
Affairs in the CIA's General Counsel's
Office. And so, you have in this army
this army of attorneys that has to
approve it before it even gets to the
president for his signature. Um
It would be easier. It would be more
legal
to put so much pressure on Maduro that
he opts to just get up and run
than it would be to try to to kill him.
And and just in the last year or so,
Pierce, there have been um what? A dozen
a dozen and a half
uh mercenaries that have sort of
washed up on shore and have said, "Hey,
we're here to overthrow Maduro." only to
be then arrested and traded back to the
United States for Venezuelan prisoners.
It's kind of silly.
Finally, the these strikes on the boats
in the Caribbean Sea. In your
estimation, are these legal and
justified or not?
No. I'm not seeing any any even efforts
at legality here. Uh by all accounts,
the intelligence is just simply not
there to show that these are uh drug
boats
or if they are drug boats that the drugs
are bound for the United States. Uh
there was a a a foot in a boot that
washed up on shore in Trinidad and
Tobago last week, and it was identified
as the foot and boot of a Trinidadian
fisherman.
Now, the family wants answers. So, you
know, I was in the CIA long enough that
I came to learn
when a CIA officer or a White House
official or a Pentagon, you know,
general says,
"Take my word for it. I've seen the
intelligence."
Don't take his word for it.
I want to play this before we finish a
clip from Pete Hegseth. He's a secretary
of state, state obviously for the war
department as it's now renamed. Let's
take a look.
So, you didn't see any survivors, to be
clear, after that first shot.
I did not personally see survivors, but
I stand cuz the thing was on fire. It
was exploded in fire and smoke. You
can't see anything. You got digital This
is called the fog of war. This is what
you in the press
don't understand. You sit in your
air-conditioned offices or up on Capitol
Hill and you nitpick and you plant fake
stories in the Washington Post about
kill everybody phrases on anonymous
sources not based in anything. Not based
in any truth at all. And then you want
to throw out really irresponsible terms
about American heroes, about the
judgment that they made. I wrote a whole
I wrote a whole book on this topic
because of what politicians and the
press does to war fighters.
The the fog of war. I mean, look, there
is a fog of war, of course there is. But
did you find that convincing?
Uh no. There there is no war. This was
just a unilateral American decision to
start bombing these boats. So, fog of
war, no. And international law is
actually very clear here. If there are
survivors who are not able to engage in
combat, you can't kill them. Why? It's
It's really quite simple.
Yeah, I agree.
Uh John Kiriakou, thank you very much
indeed for rejoining me on Uncensored.
Thank you. Good to see you again. Thank
you.
Piers Morgan Uncensored is proudly
independent. The only boss around here
is me. If you enjoy our show, then ask
for only one simple thing. Hit subscribe
on YouTube and follow Piers Morgan
Uncensored on Spotify and Apple
Podcasts. And in return, we will
continue our mission to inform,
irritate, and entertain, and we'll do it
all for free. Independent Uncensored
media has never been more critical, and
we couldn't do it without you.
[Music]